Finding Aid for the Olive Percival Papers LSC.0119
UCLA Library Special Collections
- 12. Miscellaneous
  - Spice bag, Item 13 (Box 6)
    Spice bag, rose printed voile with lace edging, filled with cloves and tied with pink and green satin ribbon.
  - Odd bits of wrapping paper, etc. decorated by OP., Item 14 (Box 6)
    - 1. Small cardboard box lid
      Small cardboard box lid (4.5 × 7.5 cm) decorated on top with cut and pasted paper - a potted plant. Note inside in green ink (by Mrs. Wright?) "From/brown/leather case."
    - 2. Odd shaped white paper
      Odd shaped white paper decorated with mask shaped paper cut-outs and paper ribbon. Ink note on back (by Mrs. Wright?) "On one of/Olive's/boxes."
    - 3. Odd shaped cardboard
      Odd shaped cardboard decorated with cut-outs of duck, elephant, birds, and strips of colored paper. Ink note on back "Box........ation by Olive Percival."
    - 4. Odd shaped paper
      Odd shaped piece of white and gold paper decorated with cut-out ducks - cerise and green. Ink note (by Mrs. Wright?) on back: "Isn't this Box/'just ducky?'/Decorated for my birthday by my dear/Olive."
    - 5. Paper
      Paper from small package - printed with flower springs, decorated with cut-outs of birds, elephant, Christmas seals, and strips of paper.
    - 6. Wrapping paper
      Wrapping paper from small package, decorated with floral print, sealed with two seals of red wax impressed with heraldic seal. Ink note inside: "Olive's lovely paper/and seals."
      [Note: 119/12/10-11-12-13-14 Gift of Mrs. George V. Wright, May 2, 1949.]
  - Print of pottery coffee pot mounted on blue paper., Item 15; 6 × 4 cm. (Box 6)
  - 11 place cards, Item 16 (Box 6)
    Set of 11 place cards made by OP of blue cardboard with gilded edges, and bowls of fruit made of paper cut and pasted.
    [Note: 119/12/15-16 Gift of Mrs. Morris Cohn (Edith Armer)
  - [Mrs. Kreider], Item 17 (Box 6)
    Note written, ink, by Mrs. Kreider, on folded paper. 1 lists OP's favorite flowers; 1 lists friends OP knew well.
  - Hymns and Songs of Praise, Item 18 (Box 6)
    3 notes from back of OP's music book Hymns and Songs of Praise [Hitchcock, Roswell D.]
- 13. Books by Olive Percival (published).
  - Mexico City, an idler's notebook., Item 1 (Box 2)
    Chicago, Herbert S. Stone & Company, 1901. 18cm. illus., plates. 208 p.
    Presentation copy to Florence Moore with Christmas greeting. Autographed, dated at Los Angeles 1909.
  - Leaf-shadows and rose-drift, being little songs from a Los Angeles garden., Item 2 (Box 2)
    Cambridge, Riverside Press, 1911. xi, 117 p. Copy no.40 Autographed "for her dearest Friend Florence Moore." 15 cm. Birthday card inserted at title page.
  - Yellowing ivy., Item 3 (Box 2)
    [Los Angeles], The Ward Ritchie Press, 1956. vi, 40 p. 20 cm. 200 copies. Presentation card inserted at title page.
- 14. Articles by Olive Percival (published)
  - Browsings in an old Book Shop., Item 1 (Box 2)
    Clipped from p.3 of The Graphic, July 18, 1914.
  - August. A poem., Item 2 (Box 2)
    Clipped from Saturday Night, August 26, 1933.
  - About Saké, and the pleasing art of saké-sets., Item 3 (Box 2)
    Clipped from The Craftsman, June 1904, p. 150.
  - The Story of Suey Ho Yee., Item 4 (Box 2)
    Published in a collection of stories entitled From the Old Pueblo and Other Tales, Los Angeles, 1902, p. 71. [disbound]
  - The Down-Hyl Claim: 1 - The Garden., Item 5 (Box 2)
    Clipped from The House Beautiful (n.d.) p. 102-104. September 1913
  - The Down-Hyl Claim: 2 - The Story of Building the House., Item 6 (Box 2)
    Clipped from The House Beautiful (n.d.) p. 36 - 39. January 1914
  - "The Lost Art of Indian Basketry", Item 7 (Box 2)
    Demarest Family Magazine. Vol. 33:4, February 1897, pp 187-191. Photostat.
  - [Collection of Children's books. [cataloged]] (Box 2)
  - Description of O.P. and the Collection [by Robert Vosper], Item 8; [4] p. (Box 2)
- 16. Books, pamphlets, etc.
  - Songs of Tristram & Yseult, Quatrains by Elizabeth Colwell. [Chicago, the author], 1907.; Item 1 (Box 6)
    [68 p., unnumbered.] No. 17 of 100 copies, autographed. 21 cm. Gift to Olive Percival from W. Irving Way, Christmas 1909. Contains OP's gift plate. Inscription on next to last page.
  - Sayings of Poor Richard., Item 2 (Box 6)
    [12 p., including covers], bound in paper, tied with yarn. 14 cm. Outside cover by OP. Presented by "Cousin Ruth Graves."
  - Recently discovered English ancestry of Governor William Tracy of Virginia 1620..., Item 3 (Box 6)
    New Haven, Journal of American History, 1908. 31 p., illus., col. plates, 28 cm. OP book plate. Contains genealogical notes, etc. inserted at back (loose) by OP. Outside cover by OP. Inserted reprint.
  - The life of Rev. David Brainerd. New York, American Tract Society, (The Evangelical Family Library, vol. 7), n.d.; Item 4 (Box 6)
    OP's bookplate inside front cover. OP's penciled note on first leaf: "One of the first Old Books I ever bought--From Ward's, where the little Bright-eyed Boy Helper was Ernest Dawson.." Added to collection Dec. 1948, Gift of Glen Dawson. Clipping from book catalogue listing three editions of Edwards' work mounted on red paper, dated 1936, and laid in book. 108 p. 15.4 cm.
  - Daisy Miller: a study. New York, Harper & Brothers, 1878.; Item 5; 116 pages, 13.5 cm. (Box 6)
    OP's bookplate inside front cover; signed by Olive Percival on first leaf, with note, in ink: From Jack/November/1937.
    Gift of Glen Dawson, February 1949.
  - Dreams and clouds. Haverford, Pennsylvania, The Balthasar Schmidt and Allied Families' association, 1927.; Item 6 (Box 6)
    No.8 of limited edition of 125 copies. Foreword signed by Alfred Percival Smith. Quarter bound in brown leather. 19 cm. OP bookplate inside front cover.]
    [See letter from Alfred Percival Smith to Olive Percival, dated June 13, 1928 119/3/20 p.19]
  - Angelo, Tyrant of Padua. The story in English and French by Charles Alfred Byrne. New York, F. Rullman, 1905.; Item 7; 27 p. paper cover, 25.5×17 cm. (Box 6)
    [To Gifts, 5/57/ PS 3503 B6377p.]
  - The Path o'life. Chicago, Carrie Jacobs Bond, 1909.; Item 8; 10 l. 1 plate. In paper back, 18 × 13 cm. (Box 6)
    Note, ink, on first leaf: "Dear Olive Percival -/There are only a few of/these little books - may/be ten-but I know you care for my simple/stories so this is yours with my love-/ Carrie Jacobs-Bond." Enclosed in Brown paper envelope.
    [Note: 119/16/7-8 Gift of Jake Zeitlin 1948-49]
  - Oration delivered in the Old South Church by Wendell Phillips Boston, Reuben Hildreth, Printer, June 14, 1876. [n.d.]; Item 9; 11 p.; In stiff paper cover. 23 × 15 cm. (Box 6)
    Inscribed in ink over title on page 1: "E. E. Newman/with kind regards of/her cousin" Bears OP's bookplate inside front cover, and two slips of paper pasted in with notes in ink by OP: "Rev./Miss Emma E. Newman/First Woman/ordained/By Congregationalists/Graduated Andover/1856-/Home Missionary to Kansas/Died 16 July, 1922/ Sierra Madre, Cal./(Cousin of Wendell Phillips)/"Lineal Descendant of/Judge Sewall-/" and "W.P./Aet./65-/"1811-/1884/"
    Letter (4 carbon copies) typed, dated August 10, 1859, from Wendell Phillips to "My dear cousin Margaret"; card written and signed by Wendell Phillips transmitting copy of sermon; and certificate dated New Boston, Mo., Mar 16, 1873 signed L. E. Newcomb; all laid in book.
  - Kate Greenaway's Almanac for 1894., Item 10 (Box 7)
    Wrapped in silver paper sealed with two red wax seals, with inscription in ink by OP on the wrapper: "For Florence Moore/From her Little Playmate/Olive/Percival."
  - Pamphlet entitled High Lights published by the Friday Morning Club, [1938].; Item 11; OP's bookplate inside front oover. "Olive Percival-" written in ink at bottom of front cover.
    [In Local Imprints.]
  - Pamphlet entitled Caroline M. Severance, Pioneer by Mary S. Gibson, published by The Friday Morning Club, 1925.; Item 12 (Box 7)
  - Brochure listing members of The Japan Society, London, 1911.; Item 13; Olive Percival's name is listed on p. 61 as a Corresponding Member. (Box [?])
  - Catalogue of Chinese paintings exhibited at The China Pavilion, Panama-Pacific International Exposition, San Francisco., Item 14
    [In Fairs Collection .]
  - T'ang Love Stories - reprint of address by S. Y. Shu., Item 15 (Box 7)
  - The Ex Libran, advertising supplement (re book-plates)., Item 16 (Box 7)
  - Longfellow - Poems on slavery, 1842.; Item 17; 31 p. In paper back, with OP bookplate. (Othertype Cat ?)
    [Note: 119/16/10 thru 17 Gift of Mrs. Florence Kreider.]
  - Henry Irving. London, The Green Sheaf, 1905.; Item 18 (Box 7)
    OP bookplate inside front cover. Inscribed, ink, by OP on first leaf: Olive Percival/ La Jolla/ 23 May/1912/From/Anna Held Heinrich/ Gift of Muir Dawson, July 1950.
  - The Repertory. Copley Theatre., Item 19 (Box 7)
    Program for week of November 19, 1923. Gift of Mrs. Kreider, July 1950.
  - Woman and the higher education. New York, Harper & Brothers Publishers, 1903.; Item 20; Inscribed on first leaf, pencil and green ink: 1935/From Olive/Hermosa Beach/ (Box 7)
    [To Gifts.]
    Gift of Mrs. George V. Wright, July 1950.
  - Home life of Poe. New York, Broadway Publishing Company, 1907.; Item 21; OP's bookplate inside front cover. (Box 7)
    See also: F585 S65j Smith, Sarah (Foster) A journal kept by Miss Sarah Foster.
- 17. Bookmarks
  - Bookmarks made by OP, Items 1 - 371 (Box 7)
    Bookmarks made by OP of colored papers, cut and mounted in designs of stylized trees, flowers, animals, castles, and bonneted and bustled ladies. Many were removed from the collection of children's books [119/15]. OP's initials or name appear in ink on nearly every bookmark. Sizes vary.
  - Six bookmarks, Items 372 - 377 (Box 7)
    Six bookmarks of various sizes decorated with cut-outs of colored paper pasted on paper ground. All marked "Olive" or "OP" in ink. One of these is contained in an envelope made of silvery green paper impressed with small diaper pattern. Gift of Mrs. George V. Wright 5/2/49
  - Envelope, Item 378 (Box 7)
    Envelope of blue paper with white dots, with ink inscription inside flap: "A Book-Mark/for/dear Jane", containing a shield-shaped paper with a face in black and colored crayon. Gift of Mrs. George V. Wright 5/2/49.
  - Five bookmarks, Items 379 - 383 (Box 7)
    Five bookmarks made of birch bark with ink drawings by OP. In envelope inscribed, ink: Book Markers/Made fr. Birch Bark/sent me from Maine/By dear Florence Moore/1916/ Gift of Mrs. Kreider, August 1949.
- 18. Bookplates and other prints.
  - Prints: bookplates, greeting cards, etc., Items 1 - 35
    Cuts from some of these prints are included in this collection [see 119/21/2]. Gift of Mrs. Florence Kreider, executrix of Olive Percival.
    [missing (?) 6/82]
  - Christmas greetings - printed in black on white paper. Dated Los Angeles, A.D. 1924.; Item 36; Paper folder, 10 × 6.5 cm. (Box 7)
  - Olive Percival's Bookplates, Item 37 (Box 4)
    Envelope marked "Olive Percival's Bookplates, containing 23 plates and seals. Gift of Mrs. George V. Wright May 2, 1949.
  - Bookplate of Wilbur Macey Stone, Item 38 (Box 4)
    Bookplate of Wilbur Macey Stone mounted on small paper (folded) bearing notation, ink, by OP: "Good Morning, once more, /Little Girl./Will you not please have a/Book-plate?/ (This man is an artist in N.Y./and, a friend of my Hartford cousin)" (In box marked "O.P.")
  - Mounted bookplates, Item 39 (Box 4)
    Mounted bookplates in paper folder, as follows:
    Dorothy Bowen
    Pauline Garner Curran
    MEC
    Mary Eleanor Curran
    Robert Garner Curran
    Hamilton B. Clark
    O. P. Clark
    Francis J. Conata(?)
    Mildred Little
    Francis Marion Pottenger
    Mary Elizabeth Waterman
    Wild Flower Club.
  - Loose bookplates, Item 40 (Box 4)
    Loose bookplates, as follows:
    Emma M. S. & James H. W. Alehouse (1)
    Rose W. Baruch (1)
    Margaret Cohn (1)
    Francis J. Conata (1)
    M.E.C. (81)
    Mary Eleanor Curran (40)
    Mary Eleanor Curran (16)
    Pauline Garner Curran (41)
    Robert Garner Curran (1)
    Kenneth Glendower Darling (2)
    Walter Desmond, Jr. (2)
    Clifford L. Graves (1)
    Edmund D. North (1)
    Francis Marion Pottenger (2)
    Nellie L. Robbins (3)
    Frank T. Scott (2)
    Mary Brooks Warner (1)
    Mary Elizabeth Waterman (1)
    H. R. W. (1)
    Robert Hanna Waterman (8)
    Presented by Wild Flower Club (6)
    [Note: Items 38 thru 40 Gift of Mrs. Florence Kreider.]
  - Bookplates, Item 41 (Box 4)
    [Gift of Mrs. Morris Cohn (Edith Armer)]
    Chloë (1)
    C. J. & M. C. Colley (3)
    Ella Correa (3)
    Gemini (1)
    Clifford L. Graves (3)
    H.M. (2)
    9 types of OP's
    Helen Mason Percival (3)
    John Luther Matheson (1)
    Charles Quitzow (2)
    G.M. (1)
    Helen Williams (2)
    Emily May Wilson (1)
  - Christmas greetings, 1923 1924, 1926.; Item 42; (in envelope) (Box 4)
    Gift of Marjorie Van Deusen, March 1950.
  - Bookplates, Item 43 (Box 4)
    Bookplates as follows:
    Olive Percival (WMS 1916)
    O.P. Textiles
    Ella Correa
    Walter Desmond Jr.
    G.M.
    H.M.
    Gift of Mrs. Henry B. Pflager, Feb. 1950. Letter of transmittal and acknowledgment herewith.
- 19. Pictures, (unframed)
  See also: Framed Pictures.
  - Post card., Item 1 (Box 31)
    Photograph of OP feeding pigeons. Written, ink, on address side: "Paname Pacific Exposition/San Diego/June-1915" and in pencil "Olive Percival."
  - Wilbur Macey Stone., Item 2 (Box 31)
    Photograph (12.5 × 8.5 cm) of elderly bearded gentleman leaning over a chair back. On back, written in green ink, "January 1938/Wilbur Macey Stone."
  - Photograph (blue) of half-timbered house, Item 3 (Box 31)
    Photograph (blue) of half-timbered house (not all of house included) with garden and trees in front, and a cat in foreground on seat or box. On back, written in ink "Olive Percival's home - the trees now are taller than the house." 7 × 10 cm.
  - Small oval photograph of OP (head and shoulders)., Item 4 (Box 31)
    Notation in pencil on back "1895 / Big Sleeve Period." 10.5 × 7.5 cm.
  - Photograph of young woman wearing bonnet and shawl, standing by a chair., Item 5 (Box 31)
    In pencil on back is noted "Anna Coleman / Grandmother of Mrs. H." 10.5 × 6 cm.
  - Photograph of young woman (head and shoulders)., Item 6 (Box 31)
    In ink on back "To Miss Percival" OP has noted, pencil, below the caption "Margaret Davis Abt. 1895." 10.5 × 6 cm.
  - Tintype of two young men dressed as frontiersmen, seated before a photographer's scenic background., Item 7; 9.5 × 6 cm. (Box 31)
  - Tintype of two young girls seated on a balustrade in front of a photographer's scenic background., Item 8; 9 × 6 cm. (Box 31)
  - Half length photograph of woman wearing a bonnet., Item 9 (Box 31)
    OP has noted, ink, on back "Miss Laura Noyes - 1887." 10.25 × 6.25 cm.
  - Full length photograph of woman standing by a chair., Item 10 (Box 31)
    On back is noted in ink "Elizabeth Bush / daughter of Sally Davis Chase." OP has noted in ink below "Cousin of the Grandmother of Abby Cromwell Hirschfeldt." 10 × 6 cm.
  - Photograph of elderly man (head and shoulders) with notation, ink, on back "William Coleman.", Item 11 (Box 31)
    Below this OP has noted, pencil, "Mrs. H's Grandfather. B. 12/13/1799." 10 × 6 cm.
  - Photograph of OP standing in her garden with a Japanese paper lantern in her hand. Dated on back in pencil, 4/18/1915.; Item 12; 17.5 × 23.5 cm. (Box 31)
  - Photograph of Mrs. Percival standing in the garden., Item 13 (Box 31)
    On back OP has noted, pencil, "Mother & Black Hawk / her devoted Cat." and "Mother & Blacky Apl/1925." 22.5 × 33 cm.
  - Photograph of Mrs. Percival standing in the garden., Item 14 (Box 31)
    Her cat "Black Hawk" at her feet. Date, pencil, on back 4/25. 34 × 24 cm.
  - Photograph of Mrs. Percival standing in the garden. Dated, pencil, on back., 4/25; Item 15; 22 × 32 cm. (Box 31)
  - Photograph of Mrs. Percival standing in the garden. Dated, pencil, on back., 4/25; Item 16; 34 × 24 cm. (Box 31)
  - Photograph of Mrs. Percival, Item 17 (Box 31)
    Photograph of Mrs. Percival standing in the garden, with back toward the camera, showing shawl draped around her shoulders. She holds an open Japanese paper parasol over her head - another stands open in the foreground. OP noted, pencil, on back: "French Marigolds / Cosmos / Pineapple Salvia / Golden Bamboo - Dec. / 25." 24 × 34 cm.
  - Photograph of Olive Percival, Item 18 (Box 31)
    Standing, three-quarter length photograph of Olive Percival dated in pencil on back in OP's hand "August/1902" 25 × 17.5
  - "Church of The Angels", Item 19 (Box 31)
    Snap shot of church, identified by OP in pencil on back, "Church of The Angels" "Abt./1900." 6 × 6 cm.
  - Photograph of OP's garden with pot of Easter lilies in left foreground., Item 20; 18 × 12 cm. (Box 31)
  - Photograph of three stalks of blossoms with vine covered cottage in background., Item 21 (Box 31)
    On reverse, written in pencil by OP: "White Foxgloves." 16 × 23 cm.
  - Photograph of two black cats standing in tall grass and flowers., Item 22 (Box 31)
    On reverse, written in pencil by OP: "In the White Forget-me-nots." 15.5 × 23 cm.
  - Photograph of wicker chair, table, potted plants on terrace., Item 23; 18.5× 19.5 cm (Box 31)
  - Photograph of garden, with wicker chair in center background, and Japanese lantern hanging from sycamore branch in left foreground., Item 24; 17.5 × 23.5 cm. (Box 31)
  - Photograph of garden with Shasta daisies, stepping stones, and large stone at left., Item 25 (Box 31)
    On reverse, written in pencil by OP: "Sun Dial/(Wrecked by Bad Boy!)" 17 × 25.5 cm.
  - Photograph of garden, with sunken pool in mid foreground surrounded by potted plants., Item 26; 17.5 × 25 cm. (Box 31)
  - Photograph of garden with black cat in middle ground - large iris blossom in foreground - sundial at middle right., Item 27; 21 × 28 cm. (Box 31)
  - Photograph of garden, with two black cats in middle ground, stone edging in background, and two lattice walls in back., Item 28; 20.5 × 26 cm. (Box 31)
    [Note: Items 18 thru 28 Gift of Miss Theresa Levy and Mrs. Lemuel Goldwater - March 4, 1949.]
  - Photographic portrait of Miss Percival, in profile, facing right., Item 29 (Box 7)
    Circular, 8 cm. diameter. Dated in ink on back: October 1892.
    A copy of this portrait is in the Photographic Negative Collection.
  - Photograph (blue print) of Miss Percival seated at a table reading., Item 30 (Box 7)
    Ink note on back: "I sat still for/several long minutes." 11.5×7.5 cm.
  - Enlargement of snap shot of flowers in OP's garden with house in the background., Item 31 (Box 7)
    Pencil note on back: "Bell Tower of White Foxgloves." 23.5 × 16 cm.
  - "Mother &/Pink Amaryllises/One Sunday Morning/long ago.", Item 32 (Box 7)
    Enlargement of snap shot - note in pencil on back: "Mother &/Pink Amaryllises/One Sunday Morning/long ago." 33 × 16 cm.
    [Note: Items 29 thru 32 Gift of Mrs. George V. Wright May 2, 1949.]
  - Snapshot (9 × 7 cm.) of OP in costume standing by entrance of her home., Item 33 (Box 7)
    On back, in ink: "Miss Percival/in a Dicken's/character."
  - Photo (blue print) of OP seated at a table in her home., Item 34; 12 × 9.5 cm. (Box 7)
  - Photo of OP in evening dress, standing, in profile., Item 35; 16 × 8 cm. (Box 7)
  - Photo of OP in evening dress, standing, head turned over shoulder., Item 36; 16 × 8 cm. (Box 7)
  - "Miss Percival's Living Room.", Item 37 (Box 7)
    Snapshot of interior marked, ink, on back: "Miss Percival's Living Room." 8.5 × 11.5 cm.
  - "These are decorated cheese/boxes by Miss Percival-", Item 38 (Box 7)
    Snapshot of decorated round wooden boxes noted in ink on back: "These are decorated cheese/boxes by Miss Percival-" 8.5 × 11.5 cm.
  - Photo similar, but not identical, to the one listed above, mounted on blue paper., Item 39; 10.5 × 13 cm. (Box 7)
    [Note: Items 33 thru 39 Gift of Mrs. Florence Kreider.]
  - "In the Days of/The Boom-/, 1887-"; Item 40 (Box 7)
    Envelope of silver paper (3 × 3.5 cm.) Inside one flap OP has written in ink: "In the Days of/The Boom-/1887-" Contains 5 tiny blue printed photos of missions.
  - Photograph of cat under tree., Item 41 (Box 7)
    Envelope of gold paper (3.5 × 5.5.cm.) Contains folder of blue paper with blue printed photograph of cat under tree.
  - Photograph of book shelves in OP's bedroom, Item 42 (Box 7)
    Blue paper folder containing blue printed photo of book shelves in OP's bedroom. 7 × 7.5 cm.
  - "Miss O'Kane/& O.P.", Item 43 (Box 7)
    Envelope made of blue paper with white dots containing blue printed photo of two women in old fashioned costumes, singing from open books. Envelope bears pencil note: "Miss O'Kane/& O.P." 6.5 × 8.5 cm.
  - Photographs of potted plants from OP's Japanese garden, Item 44 (Box 7)
    Envelope made of blue printed paper having design of Japanese character in upper left corner. Contains 5 blue printed photos of potted plants from OP's Japanese garden. 8 × 10.5 cm.
  - [Envelope of photographs], Item 45 (Box 7)
    Envelope of blue printed paper with design of birds in diamond shaped groups. Black stencil on back "O Percival". Contains the following photo prints:
    Cats on steps - noted in pencil on back by OP. 1913 and names.
    2 photos of China town.
    2 photos cottage interior
    5 photos in garden, 1 with lilies, 1 with OP's mother, 1 with yucca, 1 with hats, 1 with Japanese lanterns.
    7 photos (blue printed), 1 exterior of home, 2 interiors, 1 in garden with cat and sundial, 1 of OP with two cats, 1 of boats at San Pedro, 1 of friend in garden.
  - Small photographs mounted on paper, Item 46 (Box 7)
    Small photographs mounted on paper, as follows:
    2 of candlesticks
    1 of open book with gilded edges
    1 (blue print) of two cats with ruffs around their necks.
    1 of tea kettle
    1 of exterior of house
    1 interior showing mantel decorations
    1 of decorated cheese boxes
    1 of garden with cat.
    [Note: Items 40 thru 46 Gift of Mrs. Morris Cohn (Edith Armer)]
  - Snapshot of woman in garden., Item 47 (Box 7)
    Snapshot of woman in garden.? has written, ink, on back: "Alice-in-Wonderland"/painting the/rose bush! Observe/the Cheshire cat/who walked into/the picture with-/out ceremony./Can you see the/ploughed field in the/distance-a mile/away! Dated in pencil at bottom: 1916. Stamped: Get it at Evans's Philadelphia.
  - Snapshot of OP and two other women in automobile., Item 48 (Box 7)
    Snapshot of OP and two other women in auto (also a portion cut from another identical print - upper part) Noted, pencil, by OP: c/26/10. Note, ink: Miss Percival with/white dress. Don't/know friends/FMK
    [Note: Items 47-48 Gift of Mrs. Florence Kreider, Sept. 1949.]
  - 14 photographs of furnishings and interiors, 1 of exterior of house., Item 49 (Box 7)
    Some bearing dates and notations in OP's hand, mounted in small book with paper cover (made by OP). 14.5 cm.
  - [Japanese-made book], Item 50 (Box 7)
    Small Japanese made book with blue silk cover and red paper strip on cover containing photographs (printed in blue) of cats and kittens. 11 cm.
  - Photograph of interior with wicker chair and wall lined with shelves containing pottery and various objects., Item 51 (Box ?)
    In blue envelope noted, ink, by OP: "Photographs/of/dear Mrs. Barbour's/Lares Penates/Long Beach/She d. 7 March, 1923/
- 20. Framed Pictures
  See also 19. Pictures, unframed.
  - Photograph of standing grave-stones on a grassy hill., Item 1 (Box 31)